Slocum mss., 1955-2012 LMC 2681
Lilly Library
Slocum mss.
1955-2012
Lilly Library
Slocum, Jerry
LMC 2681
50000 Items
The Slocum mss., 1955-2012, consists of the papers of Jerry Slocum, 1931-, and the Slocum Puzzle Foundation.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired: 2009, 2010, 2011, 2012
Biographical Note
Jerry Slocum was born in Illinois and received his education at the University of Illinois and at the University of California, Los Angeles. Trained as an aerospace engineer with a minor in experimental psychology, Slocum began his career designing cockpit displays for military fighter aircraft. He served at Hughes Aircraft Company for thirty-eight years until his retirement in 1993. Slocum began collecting mechanical puzzles as a child. In 1955, he launched a lifetime of research activity on the history and design of mechanical puzzles with an article in Science & Mechanics magazine. Slocum has published several books on puzzles, including The 15 Puzzle Book, The Tangram Book, The Book of Ingenious & Diabolical Puzzles, and Puzzles Old & New. Upon his retirement, he established the Slocum Puzzle Foundation as a nonprofit public benefit corporation to promote the study of puzzles and support their use as educational tools. In 2006, Slocum announced that he would donate his world-renowned collection of over 32,000 puzzles, 4,000 puzzle-related books, and his papers to the Lilly Library.
Scope and Contents
The Slocum mss., 1955-2012, consists of the papers of Jerry Slocum and the Slocum Puzzle Foundation. Correspondence is listed in alphabetical order by name of correspondent or topic and includes letters from Will Shortz, editor of crossword puzzles for The New York Times; Martin Gardner, writer of Scientific American's popular "Mathematical Games" column for twenty-five years; and Ricky Jay, magician and actor. Research Files include subseries of materials from Jack Botermans, David Klarner, Leon Bankhoff, and Holger Larsen, all friends and colleagues of Slocum. Writings include drafts, page proofs, and accompanying research materials for Slocum's publications. The series on Patents contains photocopies of puzzle patents from 1849 to 1989. The Rubik's Cube Trial series features depositions and transcripts from the 1982 patent infringement suit in which Slocum was a key witness. Puzzle Descriptions is an extensive card file describing Jerry Slocum's puzzle collections as well as puzzles that have appeared in exhibitions. The Education series features materials on the use of puzzles in mostly K-8 classroom settings. Additionally, there are several oversized posters, prints, page proofs, and other materials.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by the following series: I. Correspondence; II. Research Files; III. Catalogs; IV. Periodicals; V. Business Records; VI. Writings; VII. Patents; VIII. Directories; IX. Rubik's Cube Trial; X. Puzzle Descriptions; XI. Education; XII. Photographs; XIII. Audio-Visual; XIV. Articles; XV. Artwork; XVI. Biographical; XVII. Posters; XVIII. Exhibitions; XIX. Miscellaneous Puzzle-Related Materials.
Related Materials
For additional information about the Lilly Library puzzle collection and other Jerry Slocum materials, see the online Guide to the Jerry Slocum Collection (http://www.indiana.edu/%7Eliblilly/overview/puzzles.shtml).
Puzzles--Collectors and collecting--Manuscripts.; Puzzles--Manuscripts.; Puzzles--Patents--Manuscripts.; Mathematical recreations--Manuscripts.; Rubik's Cube--Manuscripts.; Slocum, Jerry--Manuscripts.; Slocum, Jerry--Correspondence.; Shortz, Will, 1952- --Correspondence.; Gardner, Martin, 1914-2010--Correspondence.; Jay, Ricky--Correspondence.; Botermans, Jack--Correspondence.; Klarner, David A.--Correspondence.; Bankhoff, Leon--Correspondence.; Larsen, Holger--Correspondence.
- I. Correspondence (Box 1)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by either name of correspondent or topic of correspondence.
  - Abbott Award—Bits & Pieces (Box 1)
  - Blackman—Coffin (Box 2)
  - Coffman—Dowse (Box 3)
  - Draughon—Gardner (Box 4)
  - Gardner—Gordon (Box 5)
  - Gordon—Hordern (Box 6)
  - Hordern—Lalanne (Box 7)
  - Lamb—Nelson (Box 8)
  - Neto—Roosevelt (Box 9)
  - Roscoe—Slocum, Jack (Box 10)
  - Small—Uri (Box 11)
  - Valentine Collectors—Yoshigahara (Box 12)
  - Yoshigahara—Unidentified (Box 13)
- II. Research files (Box 13)
  - Libraries and Museums (Box 13)
    Arranged alphabetically by name of library, museum, or occupying institution.
    - Abbot Hall—American Museum of Magic (Box 13)
    - Bates College—Birmingham (Box 13)
    - Boston (Box 13)
    - Brighton & Hove (Box 13)
    - British Museum (3 folders) (Box 13)
    - Brooklyn Museum (4 folders) (Box 13)
    - Buffalo Bill Historical Center—Cumberland Toy Museum (Box 13)
    - Danish Toy Museum—Derby City (Box 14)
    - Edinburgh—Exploratorium (Box 14)
    - German Museums—Getty (Box 14)
    - Hampshire—Harvard (Box 14)
    - Henry Ford Museum—Huntington Library (Box 14)
    - Ipswich—Los Angeles Public Library (Box 14)
    - Manchester (University of)—Morgan Library (Box 14)
    - Musee des arts decoratifs—Museum of the American China Trade (Box 14)
    - Museums (general) (Box 14)
    - National Art Library (Box 14)
    - New York City (Box 14)
    - New York Historical Society—New York Public Library (Box 14)
    - Ontario Science Center—Paris (Box 14)
    - Peabody Museum—Pennsylvania (University of) (Box 14)
    - Perelman Antique Toy Museum—Philadelphia Museum of Art (Box 14)
    - Pollock's Toy Museum—Princeton (Box 14)
    - PuzzleQuest Museum Exhibit—Puzzle Research Subjects (Box 14)
    - Ryerss Library and Museum (Box 14)
    - St. Petersburg, Russia (Box 14)
    - Santa Monica Toy Museum—Smithsonian (Box 14)
    - SOAS Library—Strangers Hall (Box 14)
    - Strong Museum (Box 14)
    - Sudbury Hall—Swedish Museums (Box 14)
    - Swinton Museum—Swiss Toy Museums (Box 14)
    - Toronto—Toy Museums (U.K.) (Box 15)
    - UCLA (Box 15)
    - U.K. Museums (general) (Box 15)
    - Waterloo Library (Box 15)
    - Williamsburg Library (Box 15)
    - Winterthur—Yale (Box 15)
    - Unidentified (Box 15)
  - Non-Mechanical Puzzles (Box 18)
    - Illusions—examples, (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - Illusions—references (Box 18)
    - Stamps (Box 18)
    - Hidden images—examples (Box 18)
    - Rebus examples (Box 18)
    - Word puzzles, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - Cryptograms (Box 19)
    - Alphametics (Box 19)
    - Slant writing (Box 19)
    - Tobin's puzzle (Box 19)
    - Postcard puzzles (Box 19)
    - Puzzle cartoons (Box 19)
    - Clippings (Box 19)
    - Advertisements (Box 19)
    - Giveaways (Box 19)
    - Nature's puzzles (Box 19)
    - Teaching aids (Box 19)
    - Quilts (Box 19)
    - Songs and music (Box 19)
    - Coins (Box 19)
    - Magic (Box 19)
    - General (Box 19)
    - Electronic puzzles (Box 19)
    - Bibliography (Box 19)
    - Games (Box 19)
    - Sequence puzzles (Box 19)
    - Logic puzzles (Box 19)
    - Math puzzles, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - Mazes, (3 folders) (Box 19)
  - David Klarner materials (Box 40)
    Biographical / Historical
    David Klarner was a professor of mathematics at Stanford University and then SUNY-Binghamton until his death in 1999. He was an expert on polyominoes and also wrote extensively about Box-packing puzzles. Additionally, Klarner wrote the Foreword to Jerry Slocum's Book of Ingenious and Diabolical Puzzles.
    Boxes 40-42 in this subseries are Klarner's personal papers. Boxes 63-64 contain realia.
    - Box-packing puzzles (Box 40)
    - Martin Gardner materials (Box 40)
    - Erdos Conjecture formula (Box 40)
    - Articles, (2 folders) (Box 40)
    - Puzzle formulas, (6 folders) (Box 40)
    - Correspondence, (4 folders) (Box 40)
    - List of publications (Box 41)
    - Puzzle formulas (Box 41)
    - Mathematical Gardner materials, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - Correspondence, (5 folders) (Box 41)
    - Articles, (11 folders) (Box 41)
    - Polyomino sketches (Box 41)
    - Mathematical Gardner materials, (5 folders) (Box 42)
    - Puzzle papers (Box 42)
    - Polyominoes, (3 folders) (Box 42)
    - Pamphlets (Box 42)
    - Catalogs (Box 42)
    - Newsletters (Box 42)
    - Articles (Box 42)
    - Formulas (Box 42)
    - Puzzle party information (Box 42)
    - Wood blocks used for Box-filling experiments (Box 63)
    - Plastic legs used to hold puzzles (Box 64)
    - Tile pieces used to solve Tower of Hanoi puzzle (Box 64)
    - Posters (Box 70 (Oversize))
    - Polyomino sketches (Box 72 (Oversize))
    - Wood board solution for Hexomino tiling of 9x9 plane (Box 74 (Oversize))
  - Holger Larsen materials (Box 42)
    Holger Larsen was an avid puzzle collector with scholarly interests in the history and geography of puzzles. His collection was donated to Jerry Slocum upon his death in 2003.
    - Brikker materials, (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - Catalogs, (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - Articles (Box 42)
    - Newsclippings (Box 42)
    - List of puzzles (Box 42)
    - Correspondence, (4 folders) (Box 42)
    - Puzzle classifications (Box 42)
    - Puzzle donation (Box 42)
    - Danish puzzles (Box 42)
    - Translations (Box 42)
    - Chinese puzzles (Box 42)
  - Leon Bankoff materials (Box 65)
    Leon Bankoff was a magician, mathematician, and dentist with an interest in mechanical puzzles. His materials were given to Jerry Slocum after his death in 1997.
    Box 65 contains magic realia. Box 66 contains photographs and audio-visual materials.
    - Zombie silk (Box 65)
    - Peanut brittle (Box 65)
    - Egg trick (Box 65)
    - Milk pitcher (Box 65)
    - Miracle string (Box 65)
    - Ornaments (Box 65)
    - Silks (Box 65)
    - Thimbles (Box 65)
    - Magician's wax (Box 65)
    - Bloody finger (Box 65)
    - Card and bill tube (Box 65)
    - Linking rings (Box 65)
    - Disappearing ball (Box 65)
    - Cups and balls (Box 65)
    - Photographs (Box 66)
      - Bankoff photo album, 1977-1987 (Box 66)
    - VHS tapes (Box 66)
      - Puzzle Masters, corporate sponsorship promo (Box 66)
      - Pinball...The Beginning (Box 66)
      - Akio Kamei (Box 66)
      - Cable-car puzzle (Box 66)
      - Will Shortz on 60 Minutes (Box 66)
      - Puzzle Girl, Tape 1 (Box 66)
      - Puzzle Girl, Tape 2 (Box 66)
      - Rubik Interview: Rubik's Cube on TV (Box 66)
      - Martin Gardner: Mathemagician (Box 66)
      - Watch Your Language (Box 66)
      - Rubik's Granade (sp?) (Box 66)
      - Atlanta International Museum's Puzzles After-Dinner Show (Box 66)
      - Atlanta Puzzle Exhibit (Box 66)
      - From NOB, title in Japanese (2) (Box 66)
      - The Nature of Things and Martin Gardner: Mathemagician (Box 66)
    - Compact video cassettes (Box 66)
      - Sydney and Grandma, 1987 (Box 66)
      - Sydney in Crib, 1987 (Box 66)
      - Sydney and Hillary, Changing Diaper, 1987 (Box 66)
      - David I – Doors, 1986 (Box 66)
      - David II – Xmas Wagon, 1986 (Box 66)
      - Sydney Gray Slocum, 2 days old, 1987 (Box 66)
      - Puzzle Party 1, 1986 (Box 66)
      - Turners and Mar & Jer & Allan & Sydney, 1987 (Box 66)
      - Puzzle Exhibition, CAFM, 1987 (Box 66)
      - Puzzle Party #8, 1986 (Box 66)
  - Rubik's Cube solutions (Box 50)
    Several folders arranged alphabetically by solution developer.
    - Adams – Ahleitung (Box 50)
    - Angevine – Behrendt (Box 50)
    - Betts – Buhler (Box 50)
    - Cairns – Claxton (Box 50)
    - Cooper – Cuyler (Box 50)
    - Davidson – Easter (Box 50)
    - Fuller – Gilby (Box 50)
    - Golomb – Howlett (Box 50)
    - Isaacs – Israel (Box 50)
    - Jackson (Box 50)
    - Keri – Lees (Box 50)
    - Maddison – Mentes (Box 50)
    - Nelson – Östrup (Box 50)
    - Palo Alto Wkly. – Perjes (Box 50)
    - Perry – Richards (Box 50)
    - Roddewig – Royal (Box 50)
    - Simplified – T-82 (Box 50)
    - Takashima – Tricot (Box 50)
    - Turvill – Verma (Box 50)
    - Whitfield – Wissenschaft (Box 50)
    - Wray – Zauberwurfel (Box 50)
    - Unidentified author (Box 50)
    - Bibliography (Box 50)
    - Christoph Bandelow (Box 50)
    - Computer programs (Box 50)
    - Hordern – rotating puzzle solutions (Box 50)
    - Articles on Rubik's Cube (Box 50)
    - Singmaster – Articles and writings (Box 50)
    - Instructions and notes (Box 50)
    - Cartoons (Box 50)
    - Contests and clubs (Box 50)
    - Law suits (Box 50)
    - Dealers and prices (Box 50)
    - P. G. Continental (Box 50)
    - Gevin International (Box 50)
    - Related products (Box 50)
    - Rubik's tesseract (Box 50)
    - Bulletin de Liaison des Professeurs de Mathématiques (Box 50)
    - APMEP Bulletin 334 (Box 50)
    - Correspondence (Box 51)
    - Singmaster cube collection (Box 51)
    - Williams solving guide (Box 51)
    - Ads and articles (Box 51)
    - Correspondence with Taiwananese companies (Box 51)
    - Writings in Russian (Box 51)
    - Dunices – solution (Box 51)
    - Ideal Rubik's Cube Club materials (Box 51)
    - De Viribus Quantitbus (Box 52)
  - Jack Botermans materials (Box 75 (Oversize))
    Jack Botermans has co-authored with Jerry Slocum The Book of Ingenious and Diabolical Puzzles, New Book of Puzzles, and Puzzles Old and New.
    - Art and Pre-Prints (Box 75 (Oversize))
    - Art and Pre-Prints (Box 76 (Oversize))
  - Dic Sonneveld materials (Box 77)
    Dic Sonneveld collaborated with Jerry Slocum on The Tangram Book and The 15 Puzzle Book.
    - Census records (Box 77)
    - Lists of files (Box 77)
    - Correspondence, (7 folders) (Box 77)
    - CD lists (Box 77)
    - CD-ROMS: Articles, (5 disks) (Box 80)
  - Sam Loyd materials (Box 77)
    Sam Loyd (1841-1911) was an American inventor of puzzles and an author of puzzle books, as well as a mathematician and renowned chess player. He was falsely credited with inventing The 15 Puzzle, which many of these research materials disprove.
    - Articles (Box 77)
    - Periodicals (Box 77)
    - Newsclippings (Box 77)
    - 15 Puzzle (Box 77)
    - Articles on Loyd (Box 78 (Oversize))
    - The Puzzler, 1888 (Box 91)
    - Will Shortz research materials (Box 91)
    - Strand Magazine research, (5 folders) (Box 91)
    - Dudeney's Perplexities (Box 91)
    - Other articles (Box 91)
    - Articles and newspaper clippings (Box 94 (Oversize))
- III. Catalogs (Box 15)
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Blue Opal (Box 15)
  - Carlisle—Chessmate (Box 15)
  - Chiaro Catalogs—Class Menagerie (Box 15)
  - Cleverwood—Community Cornerstone (Box 15)
  - Constantin (Box 15)
  - Curioshoppe—DaMert (Box 15)
  - De Vreugd—Dubois (Box 15)
  - Elverson—Family Games (Box 15)
  - Fascinations—Finnish Puzzles (Box 15)
  - Garrett Collection—Gordon Bros. (Box 15)
  - Great American Puzzle Factory—Guinn (Box 15)
  - Habbermass (Box 15)
  - Hanayama—Happy Cube (Box 15)
  - Heartwood Creations (Box 15)
  - Hein Spiele—Hikimi (Box 15)
  - Hi-Q—Holland & Holland (Box 15)
  - ICube—Irby's (Box 15)
  - Jacques London (Box 15)
  - Japanese Puzzles—Jeweler's Ring (Box 15)
  - Kadon (Box 15)
  - Kamei—Karakuri (Box 15)
  - Key Curriculum Press—Koplow Games (Box 15)
  - L&M Crafts—Livewire Puzzles (Box 15)
  - Lumberjack Toys (Box 15)
  - Made in the Ozarks—Masterball (Box 15)
  - McFarland—Mr. Puzzle (Box 15)
  - Mozaika—MRM Products (Box 15)
  - Nitinol—Overy (Box 16)
  - Pioneer Puzzles—PussyCat (Box 16)
  - Puzzle Boxes—Puzzle Jugs (Box 16)
  - Puzzle Master—Puzzle Ring (Box 16)
  - Puzzles & Games—Puzzletts (Box 16)
  - Puzzling Puzzles—Quark (Box 16)
  - Raintree Puzzles—Rex Games (Box 16)
  - Rhombics—Russian Puzzles (Box 16)
  - Schneider Kubi-Games—Simpson Puzzle Challenge (Box 16)
  - Spilsbury Puzzle Co.—Swift (Box 16)
  - Stave Puzzles—Tangram Greetings (Box 16)
  - Taskmasters—Tavern Puzzle Collection (Box 16)
  - TechniQuest—Toyo Glass (Box 16)
  - Toys from Times Past—Trench Puzzles (Box 16)
  - Trevor Wood Puzzles (Box 16)
  - TW Puzzles—World Wide Games (Box 16)
  - Wu Puzzles (Box 16)
  - Adams Cube—Architest (Box 19)
  - Arjeu (Box 19)
  - Bartl—B. Dazzle (Box 19)
  - Berrocal—Bits and Pieces (Box 19)
  - Binary Arts, (2 folders) (Box 19)
  - Boardman—Bottleneck (Box 19)
  - Bits and Pieces, (2 folders) (Box 25)
  - A (Box 26)
  - B (Box 26)
  - C (Box 26)
  - D (Box 26)
  - E (Box 26)
  - F-G (Box 26)
  - H (Box 26)
  - I-J (Box 26)
  - K (Box 26)
  - L (Box 26)
  - M (Box 26)
  - N-P (Box 26)
  - R-S, (3 folders) (Box 26)
  - T (Box 26)
  - U-W (Box 26)
  - B, (8 folders) (Box 62)
  - C, (3 folders) (Box 62)
  - G-H (Box 62)
  - J (Box 62)
  - K, (3 folders) (Box 62)
  - M (Box 62)
  - P (Box 62)
  - S (Box 62)
  - W (Box 62)
- IV. Periodicals (Box 19)
  - A-D (Box 19)
  - F-G (Box 19)
  - O (Omni, 1979-1986) (Box 19)
  - O (Omni, 1987-1995) (Box 19)
  - S (Scientific American, 1988-1990) (Box 19)
  - S (Scientific American, 1994-2000) (Box 19)
  - S-T (Box 19)
  - Scientific American articles index (Box 19)
  - Scientific American articles, 1953 (Box 19)
  - Scientific American articles, 1957 (Box 19)
  - Scientific American articles, 1958 (Box 19)
  - Scientific American articles, 1959 (Box 19)
  - Scientific American articles, 1961 (Box 19)
  - Scientific American articles, 1962 (Box 19)
  - Scientific American articles, 1963 (Box 19)
  - Scientific American articles, 1964 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1965 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1966 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1967 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1969 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1970 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1972 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1973 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1974 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1975 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1976 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1977 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1981 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1982 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1985 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, 1986-1987 (Box 20)
  - Scientific American articles, undated (Box 20)
  - A (Box 61)
  - B, (2 folders) (Box 61)
  - C (Box 61)
  - E, (5 folders) (Box 61)
  - F (Box 61)
  - G (Box 61)
  - H-J (Box 61)
  - L-N (Box 61)
  - O, includes article on Slocum's puzzle collection in Omni, (2 folders) (Box 61)
  - P-S (Box 61)
  - T-U (Box 61)
  - Various titles. (Box 85 (Oversize))
  - Game & Puzzle Collectors Quarterly (4 issues), 2001-2002 (Box 88)
  - Science and Invention (5 issues), 1930-1931 (Box 88)
  - A-C (Box 93)
  - D-E (Box 93)
  - F-G (Box 93)
  - H-L (Box 93)
  - M-W (Box 93)
- V. Business Records (Box 17)
  - Acquisitions, (7 folders) (Box 17)
  - Loan forms (Box 17)
  - Condition reports, (3 folders) (Box 17)
  - Kamei Doors—invoice and accompanying materials (Box 17)
  - Poster gallery prints (Box 17)
  - Museum photos (photocopies of) (Box 17)
  - Installation instructions (Box 17)
  - Puzzle Building floor plans (Box 17)
  - Floor covering (Box 17)
  - Puzzle Building contract permits (Box 17)
  - Sun block data (Box 17)
  - General (Box 17)
  - HSBC—David Hughes (Box 24)
  - HSBC Invoices (Box 24)
  - HSBC Contract, 2005 (Box 24)
  - Canary Wharf layouts (Box 24)
  - Tangram booklets (Box 24)
  - HSBC Phase 1 (Box 24)
  - HSBC Phase 2 (Box 24)
  - HSBC Phase 3 (Box 24)
  - Tangram clearances (Box 24)
  - HSBC wall panels and security (Box 24)
  - HSBC internet access (Box 24)
  - Approved Tangram images (Box 24)
  - Approved figures and images (Box 24)
  - Tangram paradoxes (Box 24)
  - HSBC correspondence (Box 24)
  - Tangram history text (Box 24)
  - Publicity and logo (Box 24)
  - Lilly Library endowment (Box 24)
  - Tangram project (Box 24)
  - HSBC Tangram ads (Box 25)
  - Dynergy Tangram logo (Box 25)
  - Lippencott Mercer logo (Box 25)
  - HSBC Tangram images (Box 25)
  - HSBC Tangrams (Box 25)
  - Bits and Pieces, masters (Box 25)
  - Bits and Pieces, general (Box 25)
  - Bits and Pieces check payments (Box 25)
  - Bits and Pieces inventories, (4 folders) (Box 25)
  - Orders (Box 25)
  - Cognitive Concepts catalog (Box 44)
  - GM Hughes presentations, (10 folders) (Box 44)
  - Hughes work history (Box 47)
  - Presentation text, (3 folders) (Box 47)
  - Presentation slides, (12 folders) (Box 47)
  - Slide captions (Box 47)
  - Interdepartmental correspondence (Box 47)
  - Articles (Box 47)
  - Corporate studies, (2 folders) (Box 47)
  - Publicity materials (Box 47)
  - Hughesnews newsletter, July 6, 1984 (Box 92)
  - Hughes Retiree News newsletter, Fall 1995 (Box 92)
  - HSBC Tangram ads, various magazines, 2005 (Box 92)
- VI. Writings (Box 25)
  Arranged into subseries by title and includes drafts, page proofs, and accompanying research materials.
  General
  Slocum except for manuscripts by Stewart Coffin in Boxes 51-52.
  - New Book of Titles (Box 25)
    - Copyright info (Box 25)
    - Tangrams research (Box 25)
    - Research materials (Box 25)
    - Illustrations (Box 25)
    - Drafts (Box 25)
    - Reviews (Box 25)
    - Introduction to the book (Box 25)
    - Business information (Box 25)
    - Publicity (Box 25)
    - Edits, (3 folders) (Box 25)
    - Illustrations-only draft (Box 25)
  - Compendium of Checkerboard Puzzles (Box 26)
    - Master copy, (2 folders) (Box 26)
    - First edition, old master copy (Box 26)
    - Paste-up master copy (Box 26)
    - Third edition (Box 27)
    - Third edition, backup copy, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Draft, 1983 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Marked master (Box 27)
    - Prints (Box 27)
    - Replacement pages (Box 27)
    - Supplementary pages (Box 27)
    - Reference materials (Box 27)
    - Third edition, (3 folders) (Box 27)
    - Budget (Box 27)
    - References (Box 27)
    - Patents (Box 27)
  - The Book of Ingenious and Diabolical Puzzles (Box 27)
    - Solutions, (7 folders) (Box 27)
    - Reference data (Box 28)
    - Reference materials, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - More solutions, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - Puzzles—France (Box 28)
    - Put-Together Puzzles, new data (Box 28)
    - Put-Together Puzzles, reference material (Box 28)
    - Layout (Old) (Box 28)
    - Dexterity Puzzles, text (Box 28)
    - Put-Together Puzzles, text (Box 28)
    - Take-Apart Puzzles, text (Box 28)
    - Interlocking Puzzles, text (Box 28)
    - Disentanglement Puzzles, text (Box 28)
    - Sequential Puzzles, text (Box 28)
    - Vessels and Impossible Objects, text (Box 28)
    - First draft (Box 28)
    - Sequential Movement Puzzles data (Box 29)
    - Interlocking Puzzles data (Box 29)
    - Disentanglement Puzzles data (Box 29)
    - Impossible Puzzles data (Box 29)
    - Revisions (Box 29)
    - Book ideas (Box 29)
    - Correspondence (Box 29)
    - Puzzle Jugs, reference material (Box 29)
    - Unused materials (Box 29)
    - General materials (Box 29)
    - Page proofs, (10 folders) (Box 59)
    - Contracts, (2 folders) (Box 59)
  - The Tangram Book (Box 29)
    - Final proof, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Illustrations (Box 29)
    - History and origins (Box 29)
    - Corrections (Box 29)
    - Dummy proofs (Box 29)
    - Permissions (Box 29)
    - Research materials, (6 folders) (Box 30)
    - Correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 30)
    - Rough text (Box 30)
    - Research materials, (4 folders) (Box 30)
    - Butterfly tables (Box 30)
    - Tangram tables (Box 30)
    - Napoleon Tangrams, (4 folders) (Box 30)
    - Napoleon bibliography (Box 30)
    - Edgar Allan Poe (Box 30)
    - Michael Faraday (Box 30)
    - John Quincy Adams (Box 30)